<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R | Faraz Ahmadi</title>
    <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/tag/r/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://farazahmadi.github.io/tag/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>R</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright (c) `2021` Faraz Ahmadi </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://farazahmadi.github.io/images/icon_huc7cda376bf0757938c9e4b41ba46f61f_19135_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/tag/r/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Predictions of Alternate Level of Care (ALC) in Canada: From Emergency Department to the in-Hospital Stage</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/alc-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/alc-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Canada, patients who occupy hospital beds but do not require that intensity of care are called Alternate Level of Care (ALC) patients. ALC has numerous negative implications on patient health and the health care system. Early identification of patients who are at risk of becoming ALC could help decision-makers better manage the situation and alleviate this problem. This thesis evaluates the use of various ML algorithms in predicting ALC at two different time points in the patient’s trajectory. Moreover, it identifies the most important predictors of ALC in each time point and provides insights on how adding more information, at the expense of time for decision-making, would improve the predictive accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, ML methods were deployed using retrospective electronic health records. Our research is comprised of two separate algorithms at two different time points in the patient’s journey. The figure below presents the overview of the two algorithms. The first algorithm is carried in the ED stage and uses predictors available before admission to acute care hospital to predict delayed discharge in the hospital. The second algorithm uses a combination of predictors in both ED and hospital to predict the same outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/farazahmadi/machine-learning-prediction-of-alternate-level-of-care/blob/7957364c0f263d2e80325643d1118e9b47ef3754/method.png&#34; alt=&#34;method&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The work here was my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis for the degree master of science in computational science &amp;amp; engineering from &lt;strong&gt;McMaster University&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Segmentation on the Ontario population for RBC Insurance</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/rbci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/rbci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project was to understand the segments that are struggling with their health and
wellness as a result of the pandemic, and the types (or themes) of struggles they are facing or main areas of concern in order to recommend the types of supplemental services or partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was proposed by RBC Insurance as the final project for the MBA course I was taking in Fall 2020. In this project I practiced team-work in a full scale data science project. A wide range of analytical methods were use to produce knowledge from both data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two different data sets were used in this analysis. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.delvinia.com/camh-coronavirus-mental-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CAMH&lt;/a&gt; by Delvinia and the geo-demographic data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://environicsanalytics.com/en-ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Environics Analytics&lt;/a&gt;. We were given access to the latter, only for this course and project and that is why I am not sharing the report or code here. They both can be shared (without the rough data set) upon request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work here was the final group project for &lt;em&gt;M733 Marketing Analytics&lt;/em&gt; MBA course that I took in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dashboards in R using shiny and flexdashboard</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/shiny-dash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/shiny-dash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this dashboard created in R using Shiny that can be viewd live from &lt;a href=&#34;https://faraz-ahmadi.shinyapps.io/flexdb1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The link might take a while to load as it is run on a free R studio server. The dashboard contains a set of exploratory analysis and interactive charts on the airline data set.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Segmentation of the Airline Data</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/airline-segment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/airline-segment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The overall objective is to find as good a segmentation of the data as possible. Those data ask customers
for their perceptions on several attributes of air travel, their satisfaction with the airline and whether
they would recommend the airline. The attitude variables would be used for the Level 1 segmentation and the demographic variables are used for the Level 2 component of the segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the k-means algorithm to cluster the customers together. In the end, I had a tough time to personify the segments based on their level-1 and 2 results. Maybe the sample size was too low to give us good results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work here was a part of my assignments for &lt;em&gt;M733 Marketing Analytics&lt;/em&gt; course that I took in 2020. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://farazahmadi.github.io/proj/assign4.html&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; is produced using &lt;em&gt;Rstudio&lt;/em&gt; as an HTML file. You can find the code on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/farazahmadi/airline-data-segmentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict Return to Airline</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/key-drivers-airline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/key-drivers-airline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a comprehensive predictive analytics project, in which I clean and prepare the raw survey data for the analysis. Do exploratory analysis around customer&amp;rsquo;s responses, check for multicollinearity among questions in the survey and then use Logistic Regression in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.h2o.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;H2O&lt;/a&gt; to create a predictive model and identify the key drivers of return, an insight which could be used for making marketing decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://farazahmadi.github.io/proj/assign2.html&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; is produced using &lt;em&gt;Rstudio&lt;/em&gt; as an HTML file. You can find the code on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/farazahmadi/key-drivers-airline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice cream Customer&#39;s Survey Data Cleaning</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/icecream-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/icecream-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work is a preliminary data analysis task done on a survey data set done on ice cream brands. Its purpose is to clean and prepare the data set using different packages in R so that it can be used most easily by the analysts. This data set accompanies the &lt;strong&gt;“Seven Summits of Marketing Research”&lt;/strong&gt; text by Greg Allenby and Jeff Brazell. This was my first assignment for the Marketing Analysis course I had in fall 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://farazahmadi.github.io/proj/proj-html.html&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; is produced using &lt;em&gt;Rstudio&lt;/em&gt; as an HTML file. You can find the code on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/farazahmadi/Icecream-survey-cleaning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading the Seven Summits ice cream data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing to essential variables needed for analyses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treating missing values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;mice&lt;/code&gt; package for imputing missing values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;sjmisc&lt;/code&gt; package to merge the 5 datasets into one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing the statistics of the original variables against the imputed variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saving the imputed datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recombining the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renaming the screening, brand assessment, attitude and demographic variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recoding the variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saving the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Life Expectancy in Global Public Health Data</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/life-expectancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/life-expectancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was part of my data science course in Winter 2020&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
