<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>segmentation | Faraz Ahmadi</title>
    <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/tag/segmentation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://farazahmadi.github.io/tag/segmentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>segmentation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright (c) `2021` Faraz Ahmadi </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://farazahmadi.github.io/images/icon_huc7cda376bf0757938c9e4b41ba46f61f_19135_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>segmentation</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/tag/segmentation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Segmentation on the Ontario population for RBC Insurance</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/rbci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/rbci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project was to understand the segments that are struggling with their health and
wellness as a result of the pandemic, and the types (or themes) of struggles they are facing or main areas of concern in order to recommend the types of supplemental services or partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was proposed by RBC Insurance as the final project for the MBA course I was taking in Fall 2020. In this project I practiced team-work in a full scale data science project. A wide range of analytical methods were use to produce knowledge from both data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two different data sets were used in this analysis. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.delvinia.com/camh-coronavirus-mental-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CAMH&lt;/a&gt; by Delvinia and the geo-demographic data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://environicsanalytics.com/en-ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Environics Analytics&lt;/a&gt;. We were given access to the latter, only for this course and project and that is why I am not sharing the report or code here. They both can be shared (without the rough data set) upon request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work here was the final group project for &lt;em&gt;M733 Marketing Analytics&lt;/em&gt; MBA course that I took in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Segmentation of the Airline Data</title>
      <link>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/airline-segment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://farazahmadi.github.io/project/airline-segment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The overall objective is to find as good a segmentation of the data as possible. Those data ask customers
for their perceptions on several attributes of air travel, their satisfaction with the airline and whether
they would recommend the airline. The attitude variables would be used for the Level 1 segmentation and the demographic variables are used for the Level 2 component of the segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the k-means algorithm to cluster the customers together. In the end, I had a tough time to personify the segments based on their level-1 and 2 results. Maybe the sample size was too low to give us good results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work here was a part of my assignments for &lt;em&gt;M733 Marketing Analytics&lt;/em&gt; course that I took in 2020. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://farazahmadi.github.io/proj/assign4.html&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; is produced using &lt;em&gt;Rstudio&lt;/em&gt; as an HTML file. You can find the code on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/farazahmadi/airline-data-segmentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
